Wait for it to be stable, then pause the simulation, and then, for example, when I see that there is an unstable place in the sleeve, I will pause and immediately go to see if there is any problem with it.
If it is unstable during the simulation, I will continue to let it simulate.
This hole is still there when it is knocked out, it is still transparent.
And when you knock it out, you can delete it. If you don't want this version, you can delete it.
Because if you don't use this method, you can do it with the method of the same-sex marriage.
In the video of my last video of making shoes, I used the method of the same-sex marriage.
Next, we will make our jacket.
When making a jacket, we will talk about how to make a jacket.
First of all, we will make a jacket.
We will make a jacket.
We will make a jacket quickly.
When making a jacket, you will see a file that I opened.
Everyone doesn't understand why I said that it is still there when I knocked it out.
What am I talking about?
Oh, yes, making a jacket.
When making a jacket, because we have simulated the file before, and then it is stable.
But in that file, we have done a lot of content in it.
We made a triangle.
made the pants, made the belt, and made a lot of small particles.
If the files are frozen, even if the versions are frozen,
they will still affect the simulation speed.
Under such an impact, it is definitely not convenient for you to make this sealed file.
So let's look at another file,
first make the sealed one, and then put it outside the previous versions.
So here we will do the sealed one first.
As for the sealed one, we still do the same.
First, unseal the previously sealed one.
Then you can directly simulate this T-shirt, it doesn't matter, we will change it later.
Then move the shoulder line out a little bit,
because the shoulder of our model is relatively wide.
In the system, because I adjusted the size of this model,
I adjusted it to be stronger.
So the line here on the shoulder, we have to extend the shoulder line a little more.
Then, as before, modify this,
this is the curve line.
In the case of the sleeve, it has a basic principle,
that is, this point must be the highest,
this line must be the longest,
because the point of your shoulder to the elbow must be the longest line.
So, this point is the highest point.
Then, for the bottom of the page,
we can first,
pull the page a little longer,
pull it a little faster,
and then adjust the point below.
After that,
you see,
if I don't reactivate the sleeve,
I will directly simulate it,
because the sleeve is not changed,
so the voice will still change with the sleeve.
This is also why when we first learned how to change the shirt,
we said that it is best to reactivate the sleeve.
But here,
the sleeve,
we made a relatively loose style of sleeve,
then you don't need to worry too much,
it is not a tight structure,
you can slightly change it,
it is not so accurate,
there is no problem.
Then, here, you have to pay attention,
I said it before,
this foot can't be a sharp foot,
then rearrange it,
simulate it.
Let's take a look at the overall shape.
First of all, the sleeves are a little short,
we can pull the sleeves a little longer,
and if there is a sleeve,
we can make a square,
a rectangular sleeve plate.
After sewing,
I Ctrl D,
create a symmetrical plate,
then Shift F,
open the arrangement point,
arrange the plate,
and sew them together on both sides.
After sewing,
the sleeve plate is relatively loose,
we can slightly change it,
and then the overall length can also be changed.
Here, in fact, it depends on each person's preferences.
If you want this sleeve to be a little longer,
then you change it a little longer,
because the longer the sleeve,
this is in the sleeve,
because the position of the sleeve is fixed,
you see the sleeve is put here,
it won't move,
then the longer the sleeve,
the more wrinkles there are,
because the wrinkles are all distributed here.
Then,
we are going to look at this sleeve.
I don't know if you have found this kind of problem
when making sleeves.
That is,
look.
The curves here are all smooth,
but when it comes to here,
it rolls in,
right?
The curves here are all smooth,
and here,
it suddenly has a section,
so let's take a look at this place.
If this curve,
when it comes down to this entire smooth,
this section is so long,
and when it comes down to this entire smooth,
So, if we want to make a straight line here, what should we do?
If we want to make a straight line here, what should we do?
Do you have any smart friends?
First of all, we know that this line is the line on the side of the sleeve.
Now, simply put,
this line is a little bit longer.
It has this part of the line.
Right?
So, if we want to make a sleeve, what should we do with this line?
In fact, Xiao Mo, Shige Xiao Mo, has a little bit of reason,
which is to make a short version.
But, you see, our sleeve,
let's draw it again.
This line is very smooth.
Right?
Yes, I see that Shige Shige is right.
You see, this is also smooth.
Here, it has one more section.
So, let's remove this line a little bit.
Dig it out here.
For example, this small section, let's delete it.
After deleting it,
does this point automatically extend to this side?
This sleeve is smooth.
Do you understand?
So, we now have to move this point down a little bit.
Take a look.
Look carefully here.
After you have moved the line,
this side will be shortened.
But at the same time, this line will be pulled over.
So, after you have simulated it,
you have to take a look.
Do you see?
In the middle, this side is shortened.
We just dug out a part, right?
Because we moved this point down from the top.
So, after we dug out a part,
the place to connect here is flat.
Do you see?
So, everyone must pay attention.
When you change this version,
you have to change it a little bit.
Where it is long,
you have to remove it a little bit.
Instead of making the whole version longer or shorter.
Well, there is no fixed time for live streaming.
Generally, we will send a preview before live streaming.
Thank you for your support.
If you have time,
you can share our live stream with other friends.
Wait a moment.
I drink some water.
Because today's live streaming...
Thank you.
Oh, is it?
Which episode are you watching live streaming today?
After we increase the sleeves,
you can see if this sleeve is too wide.
If it is too wide, it will be shortened a little bit.
Shorter a little bit.
Then let's do the sleeve part.
First of all,
this sleeve,
we also make it flat first.
Then we cut the collar back here.
So we just delete the point in the middle of the collar.
It becomes a straight curve.
Not a straight curve,
but a straight line.
After changing to a straight line,
we pull it in front of it.
Then we fill it up little by little.
Although it looks weird at first,
but it doesn't matter.
We can change it little by little.
It can be changed into a normal version.
Then we stretch it a little longer.
Make it into a long one.
A little bit like...
A little bit like a jacket.
I did this for the process.
Then I changed the model to a white model.
Then give the clothes a color.
Let it look a little clearer.
Thank you.
Okay.
Let's take a look at it later.
First of all,
because this is us.
Because our clothes are changed from
the T-shirt that the software brought itself.
So there is still a problem.
It's the side.
It doesn't have this point.
Then we add a point to it at the waist.
Use it to separate the clothes.
It's the same logic.
Add a point here and pull it in.
Okay.
In the shadow.
Not in the shadow.
In the semi-transparent.
Alt4 can see the transparency picture.
Then click on the thinnest position of the waist.
Then refer to the blue support point in the 2D window.
Click on the point on the side.
After creating the point on the side.
Place the front and back pieces in the same position as much as possible.
Then use the edit panel tool to move this point.
If we are on the same side,
we can move it at the same time.
In this way, we can control its length.
Then pull the bottom point out a little bit.
Then it has a more beautiful curve on the side.
See?
Now our waist is going in.
Then the bottom will stretch out here.
Out.
Extend.
Thank you.
Because the writing part was also the first time I did a relatively long video.
Long live broadcast.
It's not the first time.
Anyway,
the live broadcast is relatively long.
It's also a little bit more detailed.
OK.
Let's go back to this version.
Go back to this version.
Of course,
when we were here just now,
did you find a problem?
It's the front and middle here.
I always feel that this point is quite out of place.
This point is also quite out of place.
But in the middle,
it's concave.
It can't be pulled down straight.
Right?
So we have to follow where it's not enough.
Add a point somewhere.
Then make up for the logic of this point.
So here,
let's find the middle position first.
Add a point.
After adding a point,
we drag this point.
Make up here.
Make up.
Make up enough.
Make up one.
That's where we think it's appropriate.
Then we can move this point.
Because now you see the shape of this dress will feel a little strange.
It doesn't matter.
We can add details by constantly adding details.
To make it the effect we want.
So this shape,
even if you look weird,
it doesn't matter.
OK.
Then we add a point to the bottom of the side.
So that the amount on the side
looks more obvious.
So that we can blow the wind later.
Because later,
I will use the blowing tool to do this.
This is more dynamic.
In this way,
the amount on the bottom side is a little more.
The effect will be better if it blows the wind.
See?
In fact,
the bottom side is still relatively wide.
So when we change it,
if we think the shape is a little strange,
it doesn't matter at all.
It can be understood.
Then we are going to start making the collar.
In fact,
when making the collar,
if you don't know what the shape of the collar is,
we can change it a little bit.
First of all,
we first draw a rectangular plate
and sew it up.
OK.
Then we use the editing plate tool
to measure the position of the collar.
It's this point.
In fact,
did we just make it a little bigger here?
Right?
We just created a point here
and pulled it out.
Let this curve look more like
its size is the size we want.
That's about the same as the position of our collar.
So we choose this edge
and the edge of the collar.
After selecting it,
you can see its total length
in the attribute editor.
Then create a width
is the rectangle of the total length.
The height is the width of the collar.
You can set a vertical line at will.
OK.
Then we use the line sewing machine
to sew here 1 to N.
Do you still remember
which key to press
on the sewing machine 1 to N?
Let's think about it again.
OK.
Then we use the sewing machine
to sew here.
Let's think about it again.
If we sew one edge
and many edges together,
which key to press
on the sewing machine 1 to N?
How come there is N?
What is the second key?
Only one of my friends
answered it correctly.
It is Shift Shift.
I saw the digivolution crisis
and TSC ACMR.
Correct.
You have to press the Shift key.
Let's take a look again.
Let's show it to our friends
who don't know.
This is a version.
And then
there are many versions.
OK.
For example,
this is a version of
the first version of the first version.
This is the first version.
This is the second version.
This is the third version.
This is the fourth version.
This is the fifth version.
So when we want to sew
this edge and many edges together,
we first choose
this edge of a whole edge,
and then press the Shift key.
When pressing the Shift key
and not putting it,
select the multi-section edge
and release the Shift key.
Do you understand?
Say it again.
Click on the first section.
Press Shift.
At this time,
its color changes, right?
OK.
Then we select
the multi-section with it.
You can see it.
There will be some empty lines
to indicate that
it is a section and multi-section together.
OK.
But if you are
multi-section and multi-section,
we can't use N.
We can't use the Shift key.
Because if you use the Shift key,
you can only
multi-section and multi-section.
Do you understand?
So here,
we have to press and select
M to N sewing machine.
The M to N sewing machine,
if you are multi-section and multi-section,
select the edge first.
Click.
Pay attention to the direction.
Don't turn it over like this.
The direction is right.
Do you see it?
From left to right.
After selecting this set of lines,
don't click on other lines.
Put it in the background.
Press Enter.
Then click.
Click.
Pay attention to the direction.
Finally, press Enter.
They are sewn.
Do you understand?
This is multi-section and multi-section.
This is also a line sewing machine.
The free sewing machine
is the same.
Press Enter.
Let's do it again.
If you select the wrong line,
if you press ESC,
it will remove the entire sewing machine.
Press Backspace,
which is the shortcut key,
to cancel the selection of this section.
For example, if you select the wrong line,
press Backspace,
you can re-select it.
Press ESC,
it will cancel the entire section.
Do you understand?
Okay.
After selecting one side, press Enter.
Then click.
Pay attention to the direction.
Click again.
After selecting, press Enter.
Enter is like a confirmation step.
Select one side.
After selecting, press Enter.
Select another side.
Okay.
Let's go back to the previous side.
Okay. Sew the collar.
Sew the collar.
It is a rectangle.
Then we add it.
Look.
Select this.
Sew it.
Okay.
After sewing it,
right-click and select Add to Outside.
This is the Add to Outside function we just used.
If you add it to the outside,
this version will automatically add it to the outside
and flip it over.
Because I didn't turn on the single layer display here.
If you turn on the single layer display,
you will see that this version is on the back side.
It's flipped over.
Okay.
After sewing this collar,
let's see what's wrong with this collar.
First of all, its width is not wide enough.
Second, let's take a look from the back.
It's not clear to see this way.
We can go back to the texture surface by pressing Alt2.
You can see the mode of the front and back of the version.
In this mode,
the front side of the version is,
it's just a normal color.
The back side is black or dark.
Okay.
Let's imagine that
when the collar is folded to the end,
this point will come back.
Right?
So if this side is folded to the end,
there will only be one point left,
not a section like this.
But if you want the collar to have this effect,
don't change it.
How do you turn a collar?
We just add it to the outside.
It will automatically turn over.
Wait a minute.
This is what we just did.
You may not be there just now,
so you don't know.
For example,
we have a piece of clothing right now.
It's like this.
Let's take this directly.
This is the file in the Gamut folder.
Let's freeze the version first.
Freeze the version.
Then delete the line in the middle.
Assume that it is an open version first.
Then let's find a virtual model to wear.
Okay.
Then there is a version here.
Right?
Okay.
Assume that it is an open version.
Then it will be sewn here.
Sew this section first.
Then here.
Find the equal position.
This blue point is the equal position.
Click it.
Okay.
Now if I simulate it directly,
although it can be turned over,
it won't be turned over very accurately.
Then I can turn it to the outside.
It will automatically turn over.
See?
Because it will turn along this connection position.
Okay.
If we want to turn it inside,
we add it to the inside and turn it inside.
See?
Add it to the inside or add it to the outside.
Then we can put it directly.
First of all,
I don't know TSC,
are you a user of our company CLO?
Because CLO is used for clothing.
MD does not involve food production.
We are used for users of CGTangA.
So...
We don't have this kind of setting directly into DXF.
This is the same.
Add it to the outside.
Add it to the inside.
If you match it,
just match it directly and put it there.
Understand?
For example,
you have generated these two versions yourself.
you have these two versions yourself.
Wait a minute.
When you select these two versions at the same time,
add them to the outside.
They are the same.
They will be pulled out at the same time.
Okay.
If you want to export separately,
you can select the heavy version
and export the OBJ selected in the upper left corner.
Then you can export separately.
Is the top of the clothes on each side important?
If you want to ask this,
don't ask me.
Because the needs of each user are different.
It depends on your customer
or what your company needs for this thing.
As far as I know,
most of them need TOPP.
Because you want to save face.
You want to make his face smoother.
Okay.
After we delete that point,
we can now use the edit curve tool
to drag the curve of the version.
So,
we can see the curve of the version.
Of course,
what we are doing here is a curve curve.
Later,
we will teach you how to modify this version.
So,
after we finished our version,
did you find that
I didn't sew it in the middle?
Because I didn't sew it in the middle.
The reason is that
if you sew it,
it will be difficult for you to observe
if there is any missing part
when the version is folded naturally.
Because everyone
is used to sewing in the middle
when they make clothes.
For example,
if you look at the collar here,
you can see that
there is a missing part
under the shape of the natural curve.
If at this time,
I have already sewn the back of the version
in the middle first
and simulated it,
will this collar be wrinkled?
It can't be very relaxed
or very flat.
So,
you can see that
there is a gap here.
So,
in order to check
what part of the collar is missing,
we usually sew it on one side first.
If the collar is manually folded,
sew it on the collar and the neck first.
Now,
do we have a part missing?
Then,
we just fill out the missing part.
Can you see it?
We fill it out little by little.
So,
we can see that
there is a gap here.
So,
we can see that
there is a gap here.
So,
we can see that
there is a gap here.
So,
we can see that
there is a gap here.
So,
because everyone doesn't understand the version,
my dear friends,
we can change it little by little.
Even if the version is changed
and there are some strange things,
it doesn't matter.
So,
we try to cut the version as much as possible.
Don't let it
be sewn together with too many versions at the same time.
In this case,
because the versions
will affect each other,
right?
Okay.
After we adjust it,
let's take a look at this version.
Here,
after we finished it,
we will see some problems with this version.
For example,
this side of this version,
is it flat?
Right?
It is a straight line.
So, we want it to be like this.
Generally speaking,
we don't want it to be like this.
We hope it is a triangle
or protruding.
We hope it is a connected scale.
So,
we will
adjust this curve
with the tool of the editor.
So,
we will adjust this curve
with the tool of the editor.
So,
we will adjust this curve
with the tool of the editor.
So,
we will adjust this curve
with the tool of the editor.
OK.
In addition,
let's take a look at this corner.
OK.
Is this corner
not 90 degrees?
Then,
because this version
is symmetrical,
we imagine
from this point
to the other side.
Then,
do we have to
adjust this corner
to 90 degrees?
Now,
our versions
are all shaped.
You have to adjust it
to 90 degrees
by using
the tool of the editor.
Push this side
in
so that
this corner
is 90 degrees.
Right?
So,
we will
simulate it again.
OK.
This is
the
scale
we made.
For the
scale,
we can imagine
that
the scale
of the seal
is 90 degrees.
So,
the scale
of the seal
is 90 degrees.
So,
when we build the seal,
a corner will be
protruded.
So,
we click on the X button
to create a straight line.
Then,
a break point
will be made
on each side.
Then,
we need to use
the tool of the editor
to pull this point out.
Is it a corner?
Then,
we delete
the curve point.
This is a
triangle.
What is the shape
of this triangle?
It doesn't matter.
We just need to
add a break point
on both sides.
and delete the excess curves to form a straight line.
This way, we have the first triangle.
So sometimes you may think,
well, I don't know how to make a collar.
It doesn't matter.
We can correct it little by little,
and let the collar come out.
Okay.
After we finish making one corner,
we will make the second corner.
It's the same.
Here we already have a dotted line.
Let's add another point here.
Pull out the point in the middle,
and delete the curve point.
Okay.
This is the second folded corner.
This is the point where we want the collar to come out.
After that, what we need to do is
adjust the position of these corners little by little.
For example, let them come a little closer.
This way,
it's a little bit like the collar of our coat.
Right?
Let's adjust the position of this point
to make the collar
a little bit more reasonable.
Okay.
After that,
if you want the collar to come out,
let's imagine,
if the collar comes out,
is it this side?
Because I know what the shape is like.
I have the foundation.
I can draw it directly.
If you don't know,
if you don't understand,
you don't need to draw in 2D.
Instead,
you can use
the 3D line function that I mentioned earlier.
Start from this point along this edge,
and draw a line along it.
This way,
it will eventually become
the collar we made.
See?
This is the first one.
Then this folded collar is extended.
This is another collar
that is sewn with it.
See?
So when we make the collar,
we can change it little by little.
So we...
I was scared to death.
Then we use the 3D line function
to draw a 3D line along the curve here.
Okay.
Then cut the seam.
This way,
our collar is cut open.
After that,
we will modify the curve of this collar separately.
For example,
we make this part
a 90 degree angle,
and then modify it
to make it more smooth.
See?
So we modify the curve of the collar
little by little.
Have you learned it?
How to make this collar?
Draw a rectangle first.
We sew the rectangle on it.
Then we fill in the missing places.
Then...
We...
We will erase the extra curve
and let it form a pointed corner.
See?
Okay.
After moving here,
the corner will be curved in, right?
Then erase this point.
Then it becomes a straight line.
Then we move it here slightly.
Now we can make the collar.
And if you want it to be upside down,
if these structures are upside down,
then you select the points that form these structures,
and align them to the point near the tip of the fin.
Then this point will be parallel to the whole.
In fact, you can familiarize yourself with these operations by moving these points.
So our main point is not to sew the back and center first.
Don't sew the back and center together.
There will be a loop.
But if you don't sew the back and center, there will be a problem.
Every time I make clothes, I will forget to sew the back and center.
Even if I have a limited edition, I will still forget.
So if you watch my previous live broadcasts, you will see that
I often have some operations that I sew the back and center suddenly when I have done half of the operation.
It's because sometimes I forget.
Next, let's do the structure of the shoulder.
What is the structure of the shoulder?
There are some...
Look at the tassel we made.
In some cases, the tassel does not block the tassel.
Then I observed it.
Because I saw some reference pictures of the western tassels.
I found that there are many of them.
Or those black-handed tassels.
They all have this tassel on their clothes.
So I thought we might as well add the content of this tassel.
Then let's take a look at how to make this tassel.
You can add another tassel on the collar.
But...
Well...
It's kind of weird.
Usually, there is only one collar on the tassel.
Because the collar is connected to the tassel.
We just turn it over.
Here, we separate it and the tassel to control its shape.
In the end, we will combine it with the tassel.
Here, you will see that I drew a line.
It's because I have an idea of where the tassel should be placed.
So to make a reference, I drew the inner line first.
I drew how long the tassel is in my mind.
For example, if you want the tassel to cover most of your arm in your mind.
Then you draw this reference line a little longer.
When the tassel on the bottom adds a kinda provide a fold,
But if you stretch the collar, it will be folded.
I see, you just want to have a dragon-shaped surface.
It's fine, it's just a dragon-shaped surface.
Let's draw a line in my mind.
Then I will start to think about the shape of the sheet after I have this foundation.
How wide should it be? Or how far should it be?
Anyway, I will draw the reference line first, and then I will think about where to put the sheet.
Oh, right, here I have re-enacted the collar.
Because you can see that the sheet is actually in the middle of the collar and the body.
So I finished the collar first, because I wanted to make the collar first.
The sheet was a thought that came out later.
So when I realized that I wanted to do this,
and the sheet was going to be in the middle of the collar and the body,
I decided to re-enact the collar first.
Put the sheet on the top of the dress first,
and then re-enact the collar and put the collar on it.
Okay, then I thought about where the sheet would be drawn.
I was thinking that the sheet might be a bit like a skirt.
It's like a small piece of skirt sewn on your collar.
The skirt version is a fan-shaped structure.
I just want to know where the fan is sewn from.
Since I thought that the sheet was down like this,
so the position where the sheet and the collar are sewn together is sewn to this point.
Can you understand?
Look.
I've actually combined the collar here.
But you see,
the fan is not in this position.
So my fan is only here,
the part that is blocked.
From this point to the middle,
it is sewn on the top of the body.
Okay, so we need to make a break here.
After choosing the inner line,
extend it to the line of the panel line and add a point.
Use it to make a break.
Then we measure its total length.
This is a cross-sectional line.
It's the same as drawing a skirt.
Let's draw a fan first.
This is the edge of the fan.
Let's draw a straight line.
Because of the panel line,
it must be this edge.
It's like a skirt.
Let's take a look.
It's open like a skirt.
So this edge must be longer than the edge of the fan on the collar.
Right?
Let's draw a fan like this.
Weiwei, wake up.
Weiwei, weiwei.
Then sew them together.
After that,
because they are stacked up to sew people,
take a look.
Is this panel lined up outside the clothes panel?
Oh, I suddenly found that there is no block fan.
It's pretty good.
Then we need to change our sewing line type to turn.
Why is it stacked up?
After sewing,
we move to the panel line of the sewing box.
Because our panel line is not fixed here,
plus the shape of the panel line,
it is not a square.
I didn't add it to the outside.
I used the panel line that moves to the sewing box.
Put it on manually.
Then simulate it.
When I was simulating this block fan,
did we find that there was a problem?
This block fan,
if you put it in this position now,
it is normal and correct.
But is it missing a piece?
Right?
Let's take a look.
No matter how I pull this block fan,
it is my ideal shape.
It should be placed in the front.
But now it is not enough.
So we have to make another triangle in the middle.
Right?
Because this point is already sewn.
I need a triangle here.
So when we finish sewing the panel line,
we need to think about
whether there is a missing section
or a missing area.
Since I want to make a triangle,
should I make another triangle here?
Do you understand?
Because this point is sewn to the neck.
It is sewn to this point.
It is not affected by this point.
OK.
So let's draw a triangle.
Then sew the side first.
Draw a triangle.
Then sew this side and this side.
You can sew it first.
Don't sew it directly.
If you sew it directly,
because the new panel line
is in another place in the 3D space.
So if you sew it directly,
instead of sewing it first,
the panel line will stretch in the 3D space.
What is the problem?
You may not encounter it now.
But in the future,
if you accidentally do this wrong,
it may affect it.
For example,
I have two panels now.
If I join them directly in the 3D space,
if they are not sewn together first,
can you see it?
It will stretch in the middle.
Look.
Then the question comes.
Why don't you just
lengthen this panel, right?
Let's take a look at
what this pattern looks like.
For example,
this pattern is like this.
The pattern we just drew
is a bit similar to this shape.
Right?
Okay.
If you lengthen it,
look.
Can you see it?
Its curve will change.
Will our curve
affect it here?
Look.
It will affect it.
And here,
we have already
fitted this panel here.
It is already fitted
on the back of the model.
Look.
Then let's say
add another point.
For example,
I add a point here.
You make it like this.
It is okay
if you add another point.
But it is like this.
For example,
we now put this panel
on the model.
Well,
wait a minute.
Let's slightly change
this size.
Okay.
For example,
if we sew it up like this,
right?
Let's put it here first.
Come here.
All sewed up.
Then the other panels
are frozen first.
are deleted.
Okay.
Then the other panels
are frozen.
Just now,
this little friend said,
Hey,
why can't we do this?
Look.
This panel itself
is like this
on the shoulder,
right?
I hope it will be extended
here later,
right?
But if I add a point here,
and then I extend the panel,
it will have a broken surface.
Of course,
it's okay
to simulate it at the end.
It's just that
sometimes
this broken surface
will be worn out
or some
parts of the panel
will be worn out.
So,
my personal
habit is
I like to
make a shape
like this.
Then
I will sew it up.
After sewing it up,
I will put it
over here.
Put it over here.
After that,
I will modify
this shape
separately.
OK.
I think
after this shape
is almost OK,
I will
merge
these two sides
together.
Because sometimes
if I want to shorten it,
I may
shorten a part
like this.
Then I may
affect
its angle
like this.
Of course,
you can just
add a point directly.
It's okay.
It's just that
my habit is like this.
Because I will also consider
that the panel
may have a problem
with this.
So,
I usually
add a panel
first.
Then
I think
after the effect
is OK,
I will merge
it along the line
and merge it.
OK.
For example,
I think
this amount
is still not enough.
Then
I will
pull
this panel
a little longer
and
increase
the length
of its bottom
line
like this.
OK.
For example,
this point
is a little bit
wider.
Then
take a look.
OK.
Next,
because
our previous curve
is still an old problem,
this corner
is a shoulder corner.
When we usually
look at it,
this corner is usually
a straight corner.
So,
we need to
modify
this edge.
If we make it
a curve,
this corner
can be maintained
as a straight corner
and
the corners
of other panels
will not be too strange.
That is,
the corners
of other edges
will not be too strange.
OK.
After
finalizing,
we merge
the panels.
Then
simulate it again.
This
can be put
on the
other side.
If you want to
fix
this block
piece,
you can
add a
buckle
here,
and then
add a
button
on the
top.
Then
we can
fix it
in this position
or
use the inner line
to deny it.
You can fix
the block piece.
I am here
to make it blown up
by the wind,
so there is no
need to use
the positioning ball
to pull it up
a little bit.
Then
cover it
with the wind
piece.
This is also
why I did not
merge the panels
directly after
creating the
collar.
This is because
there may be some
changes in the middle
when considering
it.
My
merge operations
are usually
adjusted
at the
end.
OK.
Then
we
merge
the panel
with the wind
piece.
This way,
the position
of our
block piece
is done.
Why
is it
almost 11 o'clock?
Weiwei,
we are going
to speed up
the progress.
Weiwei,
be careful.
We are going
to speed up
the progress.
Then
we draw
the edge of the
wind piece.
Do you remember
when I made
Ma Jia in the
front piece
before?
You have to
manually create
the line between
the panels
after you
merge the
panels.
Because you
merged the lines
first,
so here
I created
the line first.
This
piece of
clothing
has a
certain
texture
in my
mind.
This
piece of
clothing
in my
mind
must be
dark.
Secondly,
this piece of clothing
should be
very dense
and
very
dense
and
very
random.
You can see
my final product.
Is my
wrinkle
is
relatively
hard,
right?
You can see
that my
whole texture
is very
rough.
Then
it looks
like
it
looks
like
it is
not
soft
texture.
So
I need
my mind
to think
that
this
kind of
fabric
is
prone to
wrinkles
and its
wrinkles are
hard and
random.
So
first
it is not
leather.
It
is not
leather.
Because of the leather,
unless it is
extremely leather,
of course,
it doesn't matter.
Because
you can use
the material
to make it feel
like
the material of
leather.
I'm just saying
that in
real life,
this kind of
hand shape
is generally
not leather.
Generally,
it is
and this kind of
style is also
less leather.
Of course,
this is far-fetched.
I want
it to have
a lot of wrinkles
and
very hard wrinkles,
so I will
increase its
gold-plated
strength,
toe-line strength.
Let's take a look
at the gold-plated
strength.
I
increased it
from the default
27 to
the
right
one
that
Teddy Bear
said
that
it is
really
this kind of
kind of
clothes.
Then
I will
take a look at
the
material of
gold-plated
strength.
In
real life,
in general,
the
toe-line strength
is not
higher than the
quality of
the gold-plated
strength.
Whether it is
this strength
or the
bend strength
behind
it,
in general,
it is not
higher than the
strength of
gold-plated
strength.
This is
something that
I would like to
talk about
a little bit.
It is
that clothes
have their own
thread
direction.
Of course,
I have talked about
this problem
in the last
live broadcast.
For example,
if you
look at it
like this,
it is the same
unit length.
You may
have two threads
or two
threads.
This is
gold.
Whether it is
gold or
tail-thread, you will have two threads.
For example, if you have the same length, for example, it's one centimeter, you will only pass through one point diagonally here, you will not pass through two points.
Because when you stretch, the direction of the diagonal line will easily become, because we are, anyway, I think everyone should have the original knowledge, that is, the parallel and quadrilateral are more unstable.
Of course, I just explained it like this, you can think of it like this, then its diagonal is easy to stretch, you understand?
Because its, because the diagonal is not a sand, that is, the branches in our real life are all horizontal branches, and then the tail, it is horizontal to line some sand, and then the tail to line some, this color is so ugly, change another color.
Horizontal is this line, and then the tree is like this.
Horizontal is this line, right?
Then our piece of cloth is blown up like this.
Then the vertical direction is sand, and then the horizontal direction is also sand, tail and sand, right?
But your diagonal won't have a line that comes in diagonally.
In general, there won't be.
Then this vertical value is actually a kind of stretching performance that we have set.
What it represents is actually a bit similar to the density of the line of this cloth.
Then let's talk about something that everyone knows.
For example, a sweater, a sweater, your sweater is easy to stretch, right?
But if you pull the sweater diagonally, if you have a piece of clothing on your hand or you are sitting right now,
you can pull your clothes, the level can't be pulled, right? The value can't be pulled.
But if you pull it diagonally, you can pull it.
You can stop and look at the video's eyes and then stretch your hands.
Pull the clothes you are wearing now.
For example, your water, or your pants, right?
The level of your pull, the value of your pull, it may have some resistance.
But if you pull it diagonally, it will become a good pull.
Is it right?
Wuzang, Wuzang, though he is small, says no.
You see, when you learn knowledge, you don't know how to do it.
You don't know how to wear clothes, do you?
I really can't stand it.
Forget it, forget it.
Anyway, you just know it.
There is such a setting.
OK.
So, all the numbers, it is diagonal, that is, the strength of the diagonal line is actually the strength of the diagonal line direction.
That is, the strength of the stretching performance.
The first three are related to stretching performance.
This value, or the value on the diagonal line of the bending strength,
will not, in general, be greater than the strength value on the other two directions.
Do you understand?
So when you are adjusting, you have to give yourself a concept.
That is, the value of the diagonal line is a little smaller than the other two.
Anyway, just remember it like this.
OK.
Oh, it's far away.
I forgot where I was talking about.
So I have reduced the bending strength here, right?
Let's go back and talk about it again.
I explained to you before.
That is, if you, if you increase the strength of the tail gauze, the strength of the gold gauze, and the strength of the diagonal line,
you are making this fabric become difficult to stretch.
If this fabric is not easy to stretch, it will easily produce wrinkles.
Because it is more.
It is more.
It's just that it's a little bit of force.
It will produce wrinkles.
And the bending strength is that we can see the wrinkles in the flesh.
Is it thinner or thicker?
The higher the bending strength, the whole dress, including the texture of the wrinkles on the dress, is thicker.
Then if the bending strength is relatively low, the wrinkle texture of the whole dress is thinner.
OK.
Then let's explain it again.
The same stretch performance.
For example, for example, for example, the same thing that is easy to stretch.
One is a sweater.
One is.
One is a silk handkerchief.
Then you don't have to think about it.
The sweater is thicker.
The handkerchief is thinner.
Then the handkerchief will form a wrinkle.
Its bending strength is low.
Because it is thin.
And it.
It.
The whole texture is thin.
And it's easy to bend.
Because.
The whole thing.
You may be soft.
It's all that.
That's the wrinkle.
But the leather.
We don't talk about that.
Formed.
Is.
The texture of the old.
Ah.
In general.
This leather.
It's all thick.
It won't be like that handkerchief.
Just.
It's a lot of fine, small wrinkles.
It's.
Its wrinkles are all.
The wrinkles of the leather are thicker.
And the number of wrinkles is relatively small.
So.
Like.
If you.
If you want.
Well, you want this.
The clothes look thicker.
Thicker.
Or something likeיק sole.
Because f Bla.
Bankbranchen 和毛衣都容易拉伸
Because it's both hands andit's easy to stretch.
Likeli sitt肩
it's not going to
not that difficult.
For physics, you can take a look at the tutorial video of my previous video on physics.
You can see it in the manual on MD's official website.
Will there be a gap in the GPU resolution?
If you hook up the layer conflict and use the GPU in the new version,
it will be more stable than before because it will set a surface barrier.
If you use the GPU, there will be a gap resolution.
Hook up the gap resolution.
It's not the layer conflict detection, but the gap resolution.
Of course, it is now default to hook up the layer conflict detection.
If you hook up a gap resolution, it will be more stable.
But I still don't recommend that you use GPU simulation to simulate a very precise whole.
For example, like my clothes.
There is absolutely no way to simulate it with GPU simulation.
Like CPU simulation.
It's really just like a built-in GPU simulation.
And it's so stable to operate so many layers of version
If you're just doing a single layer of clothes or a layer of clothes, it's okay.
Oh, I forgot what I was going to talk about.
Then we create the inner line.
But before creating the inner line, we need to merge the lines first.
Otherwise, if you create the inner line along the line in this position, it will not be the correct inner line.
So we need to merge the lines here first.
When we merge the lines, we need to pay attention that we only merge the lines below.
The upper line is still an independent line.
After selecting the sewing line tool, right-click and select Merge.
It will merge naturally.
Can you see it? The panel is merged here.
After merging, we have a sewing line before.
It can be folded cleanly by itself.
Now, if it is folded,
if you want it to be folded more densely,
you need to create the inner line.
Then apply the folding angle to it.
Just like the folding angle we talked about before,
how do you set it?
After that, this clothes, we have the curtain layer.
Here, I choose the curtain layer to the inside.
Because our collar is already folded.
So if you choose the outer part of the curtain layer,
does it mean that you have to put another layer in this folded space?
You have to put another layer.
Then you have to put another layer in the middle of the folded part.
If you put another layer in the middle of the folded part,
it will be unstable.
So we choose the inner curtain layer to the inside.
For example, if you fold the collar like this,
we will talk about it in more detail.
I am afraid that you don't understand why I choose the inner curtain layer.
For example, this clothes is already folded.
For example, the suit.
Then I need to create a double layer to control its fold.
If I choose the outer part of the curtain layer,
you see, it will have a broken surface.
Because my collar is already folded,
it is already attached to itself.
And you can't solve this problem well through layers.
Because there is already a gap between the panels.
So when this is already folded,
we have to consider whether it will cause a gap after you use the curtain layer.
If there is a gap on the outer part of the curtain layer,
here is a gap,
we will turn it over to the inner part of the curtain layer.
See?
It is relatively better.
Understand?
So when you choose the curtain layer,
remember to consider whether it will cause this kind of gap or unstable problem.
This is a good habit to cultivate yourself.
It can also prevent some instability.
OK.
Well, let's talk about the rest.
In the back here,
we will reduce the gap thickness of these panels.
Then,
let's see if there is any instability.
If there is any instability,
immediately stop the simulation.
Then, let's solve the gap and instability.
You can also adjust the thickness of the clothes.
What is the thickness you mean?
Is it physical property?
Physical property does not affect at all.
In fact, other things do not affect.
The thickness does not affect.
You just directly adjust the thickness of the gap.
Whether you are talking about the thickness of the gap
or the thickness of the
gap,
it doesn't matter.
My own operating habits are that when I operate to the middle,
I may be used to reducing the thickness of the gap.
In this way,
I can make the panels and panels stick closer together.
It's more realistic.
However,
if you change it at the end,
sometimes the particle diameter is relatively small.
It may be stuck.
The reaction speed will be slower.
So I may change it at the beginning.
Just modify it to half.
For example,
when the particle diameter is reduced to 10,
you will see that my operating habits are usually
when the particle diameter is reduced to 15 or 10,
I will directly reduce the impact velocity at the same time.
These are all habits that have been nurtured for many years.
OK.
Here,
you will see that I give it here on the side.
I applied the elasticity.
I applied the elasticity to make the sleeve here
naturally form more folds.
So I applied the elasticity,
which is equivalent to pulling this edge up along this edge.
The more the clothes are made in the back,
the more obvious the difference in wear and tear.
That is,
there will be some problems like this
if you don't pay attention to some operating habits.
So I told you,
when you do it,
do you find that when I do it,
I will make it layer by layer.
After making a layer,
I will freeze it.
If the outer layer I made is smaller than the inner layer,
then my outer layer,
I either temporarily increase the shrink rate of the outer layer,
and then wear it with layers,
and my inner layer will freeze.
Or,
I will tighten the inner layer first,
turn it into a tight clothes,
and then put the outer layer on it.
At the same time,
I will freeze the inner layer.
Because if you let all the layers participate in the calculation at the same time,
the particles between them will collide.
These collisions will lead to the possibility of instability.
So we try to make as much instability as possible.
Don't let it collide and move
between the panels and the panels.
This is why everyone looks at me.
Basically,
in every teaching video or teaching live broadcast,
I have to freeze my panels.
This is a habit.
And you will see my mid-term.
I don't care what I do.
Basically,
my mid-term will definitely dissolve all the panels and simulate them together.
This is also to make them able to simulate each other more stably.
Simply put,
for example,
you freeze A first,
and then put B outside A.
Then your B is indeed already wearing,
that is,
the B layer of the costume is indeed already simulated stably.
But if at this time,
you don't freeze A,
and then simulate B together,
then it may happen that
after you add C and D,
in fact,
the space of the A layer can be compressed.
But because you freeze the A layer,
and then put B, C, and D on the outside of it,
so you don't know
when you do the movement change afterwards,
this A will be compressed by B, C, and D,
which are these clothes added to the outer layer.
Then some clothes,
if you compress it at many layers at the same time,
it may be unstable.
Or,
for example,
B is between A and C,
and then B is frozen all the time.
You didn't let any of them simulate each other.
When you finally add these collisions at the same time,
it may be unstable.
So,
but freezing is a function that you must use.
Because if you don't freeze,
your files may get stuck.
Because if you freeze,
it can effectively reduce some computing power.
So when I freeze,
I usually do it in the middle.
Even if there are some lags,
I must let them simulate each other again.
This is to prevent some unstable habits in the later stage.
OK.
Then this is when doing the outer layer.
We just used a fabric for it.
Right?
We just increased the strength of the gold-plated sand of the fabric.
In this way,
it is easy to form this.
You see,
this fabric,
because its gold-plated sand strength is relatively high,
so naturally,
when it is down,
the normal down form,
or you give it a little force,
for example,
you drag this plate,
it will have some wrinkles.
OK.
Then in this case,
we give it another layer of cologne,
and then the layer of cologne,
that is,
the plate on the outer layer,
not necessarily the layer of cologne,
and then the shrink rate of them,
for example,
you see,
I have increased its tail shrink rate.
After increasing the shrink rate,
will I have wrinkles?
Do you understand?
Let's take a look again.
Look,
this is the end,
this is the end of the end of the curve.
But it is a little wrinkled.
That is,
look at this cologne.
This is a little wrinkled.
Then,
the inside of this cologne,
this is the inside of this cologne,
there is a little wrinkle.
But the wrinkle is not very obvious.
We want to make this wrinkle obvious.
The way is to put it on the outside of the layer,
increase its shrink rate,
and then,
because this plate is sewn together with the plate on the inside of the layer,
its wrinkle will occur instantly.
Because it is bigger than the inside of the plate,
its wrinkles will occur instantly.
Can you see?
Here,
there is a little wrinkle,
here,
I just give it a little pull,
I just let it go.
Look,
There are some irregular folds in the outer layer.
On the one hand, it is because its physical properties are not easy to stretch,
and there will be such irregular folds.
On the other hand, it is because the outer layer is larger than the inner layer,
because we have just changed its shrinkage.
Through the different shrinkages of the inner and outer layers,
for example, the shrinkage of the outer layer is larger than 100,
for example, 102, 103.
In fact, if you give a little bit, there will already be a lot of fine folds.
At this time, if you change the action in the outer layer,
it will be noise, you know?
There will be those folds.
I really think the fold,
when the final shrinkage is 102 or 103,
the fold is a little too obvious.
So I changed its shrinkage to 101.5.
You can adjust it little by little.
Anyway, you can manually modify this value.
And then, I think that it looks like
the overall,
is a little bit thin again.
So I will increase its bending strength a little bit more,
so that its fold can be thicker and rounder.
So when I make this kind of outer layer of clothes,
I will definitely use the column layer.
Because in this case, I can use the shrinkage to do the effect.
Then save the clothes.
And then,
there is one thing to pay attention to.
Before I pour in this clothes,
you have to think about whether your clothes are unstable.
For example, before I pour in this clothes,
I have been moving this scarf all the time.
Why do I have to move the scarf here?
The coat we were wearing just now,
when we were wearing it, it was attached.
But in fact,
when the coat is worn outside these clothes,
this coat is definitely tight.
Because it was worn just now.
And then this tight coat,
if it is put outside this scarf,
it will definitely affect this scarf.
The scarf itself is easy to have some unstable places.
Its knot here,
you see, when I simulate the shape normally,
it will be a little unstable.
So in order to prevent the back of the plate from being squeezed,
the knot is squeezed into a loose shape,
or the knot is not stable,
we need to lower its particle diameter first.
Let it,
let it form a stable structure,
and then add something outside.
So here I put the particle diameter,
the particle diameter of the scarf here is reduced to 5,
and then the particle diameter of the knot is reduced to 3.
You can see,
as the number of nets increases,
in fact,
a plate like this,
like this structure,
especially when there are multiple layers,
you can increase its particle diameter
and decrease its particle diameter.
Especially this scarf,
because the lower the particle diameter,
it can effectively prevent some instability.
Then after wearing it,
we will pour this in,
ah,
the clothes are poured in.
When you pour it in,
you will see it clearly,
because we just wore it naturally, right?
In order to speed up the simulation,
to speed up the operation,
the whole set of clothes is made on another model.
Now if you pour it in directly,
is it unstable?
If it is not stable,
you have to increase the layer to 1 first,
and then turn on the model,
you wear it,
okay,
the inner layer must be frozen,
if your inner layer is not frozen,
it will definitely penetrate and be unstable.
Our inner layer is frozen,
and then wait for the outer layer to come out by itself.
Okay, after coming out,
we will encounter a problem at this time,
that is,
some of you must have encountered it when you usually use layers,
there are some grid,
it just can't come out,
right?
For example,
I am now in the back here,
it just can't come out,
it is normal,
whether you do it or I do it,
you will encounter this problem.
When you encounter this problem,
do not be nervous,
just
do not pull it manually,
because you can try manually,
but most of the time it is useless.
At this time,
we have to use
a tool called the selection grid,
which is a very common tool.
Okay,
first of all,
we need to know one thing,
that is,
the selection grid,
it can be selected in 3D space,
but it cannot be selected in the back,
or it is blocked by other versions,
it can only be selected
in the grid that you can currently see,
and then add our jacket,
it is a double-layer structure,
a double-layer structure,
if you do not select the grid in the same area,
what will happen?
For example,
now it is a double-layer structure,
for example,
this version,
let's divide the surface here,
for example,
now,
this version,
I need to select these two at the same time,
then if I use the selection grid,
it can only select the grid that I can see,
based on the perspective I see,
the selected grid,
it cannot be selected in the back,
and then I move the version,
if,
because I am a double-layer structure,
it can only be selected in the back,
then the middle part,
I can not select it,
right?
Especially when I control the dragon layer,
I can not select this layer,
then when encountering such a problem,
we need to be like in the video,
put them together first,
and then in the two-dimensional space,
choose a large area horizontally,
so that we can ensure that
the internal and external layers are selected in the same position,
will not be selected more or less,
and then in the case of the same selection,
pull this grid out,
when you pull it out,
you have to pay attention,
do not,
you see,
when I pulled it out for the first time,
for example,
when I pulled it out,
is there a crack,
right?
My outer layer is stable,
but there must be some cracks on the inner layer,
then we just try to avoid this,
very obvious cracks appear,
and then simulate it,
okay,
the grid on the back is pulled out,
then on this side,
we are the same,
put this board in place first,
put the board back in place,
then use the selection grid tool,
try to put them together first,
select this area,
select it at the same time,
pull it out,
and then simulate it,
understand?
This is the way we select the grid,
this is the way we select the grid,
and then using the selection grid tool,
pull the board out,
okay,
here,
use the selection grid tool,
to pull out the region sheet,
okay,
at this time,
in the process of simulation,
when pulling,
you have to be a little careful,
right,
so if you have a conflict in the board,
penetrating,
If there is a gap in the entire grid, then use the selection grid tool to pull the grid into the grid.
Like me here, you see, my inner and outer layers are here.
Why do I use the selection grid? Let me explain to you.
In fact, you can see that if you are here, you will see that my inner and outer layers are different, right?
After the inner and outer layers are different, if I want to set this layer,
then what will happen to this layer? First of all, I have to set the layer of the collar.
Secondly, I have to set the layer of the shawl, the layer of the windbreaker.
Then I have to set the layer of this board, and then I have to set the layer of this board inside.
Only then can I make sure that it may be able to pass through this board.
If I set the layer like this, it will be very troublesome.
I have to calculate, oh, this is 1, this is 2, this is 3, this is...
In the end, I choose to twist the virtual space.
Oh, it's not twisting the virtual space, it's choosing the grid.
Then select this piece.
Use the selection grid to pull these interlocking parts out.
After pulling it out, it will be stable.
And you can see that because of our outer layers,
you can see that there is no shrinkage.
It's more than the inner layer.
So you can see here, through some of our, whether it's the back posture,
or some of the inner and outer layers, and the place where we wear it,
there are actually a lot of wrinkles here.
Okay, and then we'll simulate it and wait for it to stabilize.